opnsense.org 2019-04-24

# Privacy Statement - OPNsense, Your Next Open Source Firewall

Our online privacy statement is designed to inform you about our collection and use of personal data on this website. It can occur that our privacy statement needs to be updated. The latest version of our privacy statement is always available on our website.

**Who collects your personal data?**  
The open source project OPNsense and its website opnsense.org are operated by Deciso B.V.  
Deciso B.V. (further: 'we') collects and processes personal data.  
Deciso B.V. is located at Burgemeester Mijslaan 2, 3241 XA Middelharnis, the Netherlands.

**What personal data do we collect?**  
To operate this website we only collect administrative information such as IP addresses.  
In addition, we also use the data for optimizing our website, combating abuse and obtaining visitor statistics.

**With whom do we share personal data?**  
We may also disclose your personal information to processors who assist us with our website and who are subject to contractual confidentiality requirements and who comply with the rules of the regulation.  
From time to time, we may disclose the personal information you provide to us in order to comply with legal or regulatory obligations.

**What security measures do we apply?**  
We use appropriate technical and organizational measures, including advanced technology, to protect personal information collected online from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction.

**What are your rights?**  
You have the right to access, modify and delete your personal data. In addition, you have the right to data portability. This means that you must be able to obtain your personal data easily in order to be able to pass it on to another organization.  
In order to access, delete or correct your personal data, or to exercise your right to data portability, please send an e-mail to privacy@deciso.com . We will process your request within 4 weeks. Additional identification may also be required for the purpose of verifying the legitimacy of the request.

**What cookies do we use?**  
In order to make the use of our website extra interesting for you and to be able to use certain functions, we use so-called cookies on several pages of our site.  
Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer. Some of the cookies used by us are deleted after the browser session has ended, i.e. after your browser has been closed (so-called session cookies). Other cookies remain stored on your computer and allow us and our partner companies to recognize your browser on your next visit (persistent cookies). You can set your browser so that you are informed about the use of cookies and that in each case you can decide to accept them or refuse the use of cookies in that case or in general. If you do not accept cookies, the functionality of our website may be restricted. We do not use cookies for re-marketing purposes.

**How long do we store your personal data?**  
We retain your personal data for as long as it is necessary to carry out the activities for which we have collected the personal data. We may need to retain your personal information for a longer period of time in order to comply with legal obligations.

**What can you do if you have a complaint?**  
If you believe that we are not processing your personal data correctly, please send an e-mail to privacy@deciso.com .

Middelharnis, May 24, 2018
